Guide to the David Smith Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Sermons, 1796-1859; Series II; 5.21; 13 boxes
  - Numbered Sermons
    - Nos. {1074, [no number]}, 1830, 1850 (Box 11, Folder 86)
      1074: "For New Year"; [no number]: "For Thanksgiving."
    - Nos. {1082-1083}, {1084-1085}, {1089, 1091-1092}, 1831 (Box 11, Folder 87)
      1082: "Regeneration"; 1084-1085: "Fast Sermons."
    - Nos. {1093, 1099}, {1103, 1105, 1129}, {1114-1116}, 1831–1837 (Box 12, Folder 88)
      1093: Sacramental; 1099: "Regeneration the work of God"; 1105: "The word of God as light to dispell moral darkness"; 1114: "The importance of trusting in God" (preached at least nineteen times); 1115: "The importance of following Christ"; 1116: "Perseverance of Saints."
    - Nos. {1114-1120, 1122}, 1834–1835 (Box 12, Folder 89)
      Sermons on the "Decrees of God." Preface: "The following sermons on the Decrees of God were written & preached in 1810. - Nos. 1114, 1115, 1116, 1117, 1118, 1119, 1121. They were written in shorthand & abbreviations & much not written. I have now, Dec 1834 written them out in full with additions & for my own amusement, that they may be read by my children." No. 1122: "The sovereignty of God in the salvation of sinners."
    - Nos. 1120, {1123-1124}, {1126-1128}, 1834–1836 (Box 12, Folder 90)
      1120: "Last day of the year"; 1123-1124: "United for successful Sabbath."
    - Nos. {1130, 1132-1133}, 1131, {1134-1135}, {1136-1137}, 1837–1839 (Box 12, Folder 91)
      1131: "The Duties of a Minister & People," first part of foreword: "I would not on this occasion introduce any abstruse or metaphysical subject, but in a plain & simple manner, state the mutual duties of a minister & people."; 1134: "God's universal dominion a cause for joy"; 1136: "On the vanity of the world" (preached at least thirteen times); 1137: preached at least sixteen times.
    - Nos. 1138, {1139, 1144, 1153}, 1140, 1143, 1839–1843 (Box 12, Folder 92)
      1139: "Free Agency & Divine Sovereignty"; 1153: "Sacramental."
    - Nos. {1156-1157}, {1158, 1161}, {1159-1160}, 1163, 1845 (Box 12, Folder 93)
      1161: "To Youth"; 1159: "Sacramental"; 1160: "On Divine Providence"; 1163: "Election, Decrees & Perseverance."
    - Nos. {1164-1165}, {1167, 1171}, {1179}, 1846–1847 (Box 12, Folder 94)
      1164-1165: "Divine economy"; "God's Incarnation."
  - Discourses on Salvation
    "A Series of Discourses containing the principal doctrines comprized in the word of God, relating to man's salvation. Begun March 1819."
    - Volume I: Nos. {736-737, 804, 808, 812, 818-819, 822-826}, 1819–1823 (Box 13, Folder 95)
      Vol. I sermons numbered from 1 to 12.
    - Volume II: Nos. {828, 830, 832, 834, 843, 865-866, 868, 870-872, 962}, 1823–1827 (Box 13, Folder 96)
      Vol. II sermons numbered from 13 to 24.
    - Volume III: Nos. {25 to 28}, 1843 (Box 13, Folder 97)
      25: "The Church of God"; 27: "On The Providence of God."
  - Other Sermons
    The volumes filed here are filed by year, with miscellaneous fragments and notes filed at the end.
    - Sermons for 1825, 1831, 1842, 1848, and 1849, 1825–1849 (Box 13, Folder 98)
      1825: "Sacramental"; 1831: "Regeneration"; 1842: "A Temperance Sermon"; 1848: "A Sermon preparatory to the Ordination of a minister of the Gospel"; {1849, 1849: "Regeneration"}.
    - Sermons for 1850 and 1851, 1850–1851 (Box 13, Folder 99)
      1850: "Divine Sovereignty"; 1851: "On the nature & importance of the Divine Law" (cover labeled 1852).
    - Sermons for 1852, 1854, 1855, and 1856, 1852–1856 (Box 13, Folder 100)
      1854: "The importance of early religious instruction"; 1855: "Regeneration the work of God"; {1856: "On Divine Prescience"; 1856: "Sacramental"}; 1856: "A New-Year Sermon" noted at end: "In my 90th year."
    - Sermons for 1857, 1858, and 1859, 1857–1859 (Box 13, Folder 101)
      {Title: "On the Sabbath" - 1857: "Advantages of the Sabbath", 1858, 1859: "On the commencement of the Sabbath"}, 1858: "An Ordination Sermon. The office & work of a minister of Christ."; 1858: On "Allegory."
    - Sermons for 1859 (Box 14, Folder 102)
      "Man's Depravity" and "For Thanksgiving."
    - Address delivered at Poultney [Vermont?], 1797 January 22 (Box 14, Folder 103)
      Possibly additional closing words to unidentified sermon.
    - "The Duties of a Minister and People", 1837 January 31 (Box 14, Folder 104)
      Sermon delivered at Danbury, Connecticut, on January 31, 1837, at the installation of Rev. Rollin S. Stone by David Smith.
    - Sermon drafts or preaching notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 105)
      Three autograph drafts, one marked as preached in 1822.
    - Sermon fragments, 1810–1829 (Box 14, Folder 106)
      Five autograph fragments.
    - Funeral address fragments, undated (Box 14, Folder 107)
      Four autograph notes.
    - Bible verses by topic or occasion, undated (Box 14, Folder 108)
      Autograph notes.